Valentinus Mahendra Aaron Quendangen

Surabaya - Indonesia | aaronvalentinus@qmail.com | +62 83114602668 | https://ronaaron61.github.io/about/

About me

A person who is motivated to work hard to achieve success and gain new experiences. Interested in the robotics, engineering and medical fields. During my studies in the Biomedical Engineering department I learned many things, such as programming (C++, Python, Matlab, JavaScript), microcontrollers, digital and analog electronics, anatomy, physiology and control systems. Sometimes, I like to make small personal project.

Experience

Community service activities (Pengmas) | September 2022

• Training on the Design and Construction of Audiovisual Based Fatigue Detection Tools to Improve Work Quality and Health for Students in Trenggalek Regency, East Java Province.

Program Merdeka Belajar Kampus Merdeka (MBKM) Matching Fund | September 2022 - January 2022

X-Mano (Exoskeleton Hand Robot) for Movement Therapy of Post-Stroke Patients. Part of the MBKM activities
held by the Minister of Education and Culture. This project is a collaboration between IBEReality and Airlangga
University to develop an exoskeleton hand to help post-stroke patients.

Research Engineer Assistant - Neonatal Research Group FK Universitas Airlangga | August 2023 - January 2024

 Assisting in the development of research on the Smart Phototherapy System Airlangga Bilirubin Nesting (AirBiliNest), which is a phototherapy tool for jaundiced babies. Assist in assembling and testing the prototype as well as implementing the MBKM Matching Fund events related to this device.

Achivement

- Best team work at Sebelas Maret International IoT Challange 2021
- Silver award for iMIT SIC 2021 (4th International Malaysia-Indonesia-Thailand Symposioum on Innovation and Creativity 2021) held by UiTM Cawangan Malaysia
 - 3d (Three-Dimensional) Lung Cancer Detection and Identification Based On Mixed Reality

Organization

- FORMAT (Faculty Press Organization)
 - Design dan Layouter
- BKK (Faculty Catholic Organization)
 - MEDINFO (Media and Information)
 - Head of Human Resources Development

Skill

Programming (Python/MicroPython, C++/Arduino, Matlab, HTML) | Arduino, ESP, Analog Discovery | Laser cutting, Basic electronic, Electrical circuits, analog and digital electronics, Soldering, PCB design, Graphic design

Language

- Indonesia
- English (Unair ELPT: 540)

Education

Universitas Airlangga | 2019-2023

Biomedical Engineering – Medical Instrumentation

GPA/IPK: 3.68

Some of what I Learned: Programming and biomedical computing (C++, Python, Matlab), digital and analog electronics, control systems, intelligent systems, signal processing, biomaterials, Embedded Systems, anatomy and physiology